(480)580-8588

Paul.R.Reesman@gmail.com

Objective

A young software engineer who has experience in IHE healthcare and enterprise systems. I am experienced with distributed systems, multithreaded systems, parallel programming, and concurrent programming. Proficient in the following languages: Python, PHP, SQL, Java, C, C++, C#, Cache ObjectScript, and OpenMP. Secret Clearance.

Professional Experience

Seattle Children's Hospital

1/2016-Present

Seattle, WA

- ${\bf Application\ Developer\ -\ HIE}$
- Full Stack Developer using ReactJS, Cache Objectscript, Bash, PHP, and Python.
- Wrote PHP to integrate our systems with Okta to allow a single signon service.
- Used ReactJS to create a dynamic front end interface for our applications.
- Architected and implemented a RESTful API using ObjectScript allowing for Cross Domain calls.
- Complied with HIPAA security protocols.
- Wrote Bash scripts to remotely track Linux filesystem usage.
- Managed our Atlassian suite of apps including Jira, Bitbucket, Bamboo, Confluence, and Fisheye.

Coding With Kids

3/2016-Present

Instructor

Seattle, WA

- Teach children from early elementary school through high school the art and science behind computer science.
- Teach children how to code with Scratch, Python, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.

Oregon State University

7/2014 - 12/2015

Undergraduate Researcher

Corvallis, OR

- Refactored C# code to provide better functionality for the Targeting Emulator.
- Implemented 4 different user interfaces in order for the field tests to be possible.
- Collected data from field tests with human subjects.
- Collaborated with a set of multi-disciplined engineers and non-technical personnel which provided a successful experiment.
- Analyzed and interpreted data from field tests using a self-built parser.

Arizona State University

6/2013 - 10/2013

Undergraduate Researcher

Tempe, AZ

- Designed a paradigm and set my overall goal for the summer which included the successful navigation of a NAO robot through a maze.
- Created a simple artificial intelligence program using multiple languages which efficiently separated the machine modules and the planning module.

Forward Observer / Team Leader

Fort Lewis, WA

- Assigned to 75th Ranger Regiment and granted secret clearance due to sensitive duties required of a Ranger Forward Observer.
- Maintained positive control and accountability of over \$350,000 worth of equipment.
- Awarded the Joint Service Commendation Medal for controlling multiple aircraft which allowed for the success of countless special operations missions.
- Took charge of 25 to 30 personnel during exhaustive details which was instrumental for the logistics of ongoing special operations missions.

Projects

Elemental Technologies Splunk App

- Senior Design Project which I was teamed up with 3 other computer scientist seniors. I was chosen to develop Splunk queries and test the app.
- Wrote a Splunk application to collect metrics from Elemental Technologies services and provide insight into a customer's usage of said product.
- The Django web framework was used in combination with Python scripts to retrieve and display data through Splunk's powerful search and analytics.
- Designed queries to retrieve metrics from the Splunk database and visualize the data every 30 to 60 seconds.
- Designated as the QA professional on the team Tested all code with multiple testing techniques including regression, integration, and usability testing.
- Used Microsoft Project as our Project Management Tool in order to assign, update, and complete tasks on a timeline in order to meet a deadline.

Scandinavian Festival Booth Tool

- Implemented a tool to perform front and back end restaurant transactions over an ad-hoc network.
- Designed the program to predict future customer transactions by using supervised machine learning linear regression techniques (implemented with the Numpy framework).
- Provided a friendly interface using the Tkinter GUI framework.

NASA Microgravity Team (ASU Dust Devils 2014)

- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team of engineers and non-engineers to formulate, design, and execute an experiment in microgravity.
- Designed and developed a systematic way to use a computer system to track and record the experiment while undergoing several 25 to 30 second weightless intervals.
- Solved the bandwidth problem by using 8 GoPro cameras simultaneously, each with their own local memory in order to evaporate the need of a high speed buffer management system.

Education

Oregon State University - College of Engineering

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

December 2015 Major GPA: 3.38

Honor Roll